Guide to the E. L. Doctorow Papers 1931-2016 MSS.056
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XVI. Printed Material
  - Hemingway, Ernest. For Whom the Bell Tolls. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons., 1940 (Box 126)
  - Artaud, Antonin. The Theater and its Double. New York: Grove Press., 1958 (Box 126)
  - Hemingway, Ernest. The Garden of Eden. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons., 1986 (Box 126)
  - Brown, John. The Making of a Revolutionary. New York: Grosset and Dunlap., 1971 (Box 126)
  - Yeats, W.B. Collected Plays. London: Macmillan and Co., 1953 (Box 126)
  - Lubbock, Percy. The Craft of Fiction. New York: The Viking Press., 1957 (Box 126)
  - Woolf, Virginia. The Waves. New York: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich., 1959 (Box 126)
  - Kundera, Milan. The Unbearable Lightness of Being. New York: Harper and Row., 1984 (Box 126)
  - Soloman, Maynard. Mozart. New York: Harper Collins., 1995 (Box 126)
  - The Mailer Review. Fall., 2011 (Box 126)
  - Alighieri, Dante and Allen Mandelbaum (trans). Inferno. Toronto: Bantam Classics., 1982 (Box 126)
  - Crane, Milton (ed). 50 Great Short Stories. Toronto: Bantam Books., 1983 (Box 126)
  - One Story. No. 179, 148, 149, 154, 136., 2010-2013 (Box 126)
  - Leadership Conference of Secular and Humanistic Jews: Ethical and Professional Standards. (Box 126)
  - The Dial Reader., 1995 (Box 126)
  - Ark / Angel. Fall 1992, Spring 1990, Number X, Volume VI., 1990-1994 (Box 126)
  - Washington Square. Winter 2002, Winter/ Spring 2012., 2002-2012 (Box 126)
  - The Kenyon Review. Vol. VI. No. 3., 1984 (Box 126)
  - Bellevue Literary Review. Vol. 6, No. 2., Vol. 7, No. 1-2, Vol. 9, No. 2., Vol. 10, No. 1-2., Vol. 11, No. 1-2., Vol. 12, No. 1-2., Vol. 13, No. 1-2., Vol. 14. No. 1., 2006-2014 (Box 127)
  - The Massachusetts Review. Vol. XXXII. No. 4., 1991-1992 (Box 127)
  - The Crescent Review. Vol. 16, No. 1., 1998 (Box 127)
  - Southwest Review. Vol. 62, No. 4., 1977 (Box 127)
  - AGNI. Vol. 72., 2010 (Box 127)
  - Salmagundi. Nos. 162-163., 2009 (Box 127)
  - Leviathan. Vol. 4, Nos. 1-2., 2002 (Box 127)
  - Literati. Vol. 1 No. 1., 1988 (Box 127)
  - Ark. Vol. 5., 1991 (Box 127)
  - The Mailer Review. Fall., 2013 (Box 127)
  - Gramma. Vol. 1., 1993 (Box 127)
  - The North Stone Review. No. 12., 1995 (Box 127)
  - The Bronx County Historical Society Journal. Vol. XXVI, No. 1., 1989 (Box 127)
  - The Broome Street Review. No. 4., 2011 (Box 127)
  - Washington Square. Issue 14, 19., 2004-2007 (Box 127)
  - Dissent China. Summer., 1989 (Box 127)
  - Melville Society Extracts. No. 122., 2002 (Box 127)
  - The Berlin Journal. No. 12., 2006 (Box 127)
  - New York Stories. Winter., 2000 (Box 127)
  - The Atlantic. April., 1988 (Box 127)
  - US News and World Report. October 7., 1991 (Box 127)
  - Gettysburg. Winter., 2009 (Box 127)
  - Graves, Robert and Raphael Patai. Hebrew Myths: The Book of Genesis. New York: McGraw-Hill Book Company., 1966 (Box 131)
  - Schumpeter, Joseph A. Capitalism, Socialism and Democracy. New York: Harper Torchbooks., 1950 (Box 131)
  - The Brothers Stadnik. The Noble Manifesto. 2005: David Stadnik and Jason Stadnik. (Box 131)
  - Chomsky, Noam. Problems of Knowledge and Freedom. New York: Vintage Books., 1971 (Box 131)
  - Meltzer, Milton. Brother, Can You Spare a Dime. New York: Random House., 1969 (Box 131)
  - Eastman, Arthur M. (ed). The Norton Reader, 6th Edition. New York: W.W. Norton and Company., 1984 (Box 131)
  - Arendt, Hannah. The Life of the Mind. New York: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich., 1978 (Box 131)
  - Robinson, Paul A. The Freudian Left. New York: Harper Colophon Books., 1970 (Box 131)
  - Stern, Richard (ed). Honey and Wax. Chicago: The University of Chicago Press., 1966 (Box 131)
  - Buber, Martin. I and Thou. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons., 1970 (Box 131)
  - Dickey, Christopher. Innocent Blood. New York: Simon and Schuster., 1997 (Box 131)
  - Kurzweil, Edith and William Phillips (eds). Writers and Politics. Boston: Routledge and Keagan Paul., 1983 (Box 131)
  - Trigoboff, Joseph. Rumble in Brooklyn., 2010 (Box 131)
  - Blechman, R.O. The Book of Jonah. New York: Stewart, Tabori and Chang., 1997 (Box 131)
  - Hemingway, Ernest. For Whom the Bell Tolls. New York: Collier Books., 1968 (Box 131)
  - O'Brien, Geoffrey. The Reader's Catalog. New York: The Reader's Catalog., 1989 (Box 131)
  - Brown, Wesley and Amy Ling (ed). Imagining America. New York: Persea Books., 1991 (Box 134)
  - Thomas, Dylan. Collected Poems. New York: New Directions Books., 1953 (Box 134)
  - St. Martin, Hardie (ed). Roots and Wings. New York: Harper and Row, Publishers., 1976 (Box 134)
  - Bates, Marston. Gluttons and Libertines. New York: Random House., 1967 (Box 134)
  - Nace, Ted. Gangs of America. San Francisco: Berrett-Koehler Publishers., 2003 (Box 134)
  - Bloch, Chana and Stephen Mitchell (eds). The Selected Poetry of Yehuda Amichai. New York: Harper and Row, Publishers., 1986 (Box 134)
  - Hamburger, Robert. All the Lonely People. New Haven: Tricknor and Fields., 1983 (Box 134)
  - Goodman, Mattew. The Sun and the Moon. New York: Basic Books., 2008 (Box 134)
  - Lequeur, Walter. Weimar. New York: Capricorn Books., 1976 (Box 134)
  - Rice, Edward. John Frum He Come. New York: Doubleday., 1974 (Box 134)
  - The Minetta Review., 1988-1990 (Box 134)
  - The Florence Gould Lectures. Vols. VI, VIII, Special Volume., 2002-2007 (Box 134)
  - The Edgar Allan Poe Review. Vol. XI, No. 2, 2010 (Box 134)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences Bulletin., 2004-2007 (Box 134)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences. The Heart of the Matter., 2013 (Box 134)
  - Pickering, James H and Jeffrey D. Hoeper (eds). Literature (2e). New York: Macmillan Publishing Company., 1986 (Box 135)
  - Hochschild, Adam. The Unquiet Ghost. New York: Viking Books., 1994 (Box 135)
  - Lewis, R.W.B. The Jameses. New York: Farrar, Straus and Giroux., 1991 (Box 135)
  - Turner, Louis. Multinational Companies and the Third World. New York: Hill and Wang., 1973 (Box 135)
  - Mitchell, Joseph. Up in the Old Hotel. New York: Pantheon Books., 1992 (Box 135)
  - Greider, William. One World, Ready or Not. New York: Simon and Schuster., 1997 (Box 135)
  - Coover, Robert. John's Wife. New York: Simon and Schuster., 1996 (Box 135)
  - Hibbert, Christopher. The Days of the French Revolution. New York: Morrow Quill Paperbacks., 1981 (Box 135)
  - Merrill, James. The Changing Light at the Sandover. New York: Alfred A. Knopf., 1993 (Box 135)
  - Brady, Philip. Forged Correspondences. Binghamton: New Myths Press., 1996 (Box 135)
  - Gillespie, Angus Kress and Michael Aaron Rockland. Looking for America on the New Jersey Turnpike. New Brunswick: Rutgers University Press., 1989 (Box 135)
  - Keeley, Edmund and Philip Sherrard (eds). Voices of Modern Greece. Princeton: Princeton University Press., 1981 (Box 135)
  - Einstein Forum. (Box 136)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences Bulletin., 2008-2013 (Box 136)
  - Morris, Mary. The Waiting Room. New York: Doubleday., 1989 (Box 136)
  - Herschler, Mildred Barger. The Walk into the Morning. New York: Tom Doherty Associates., 1993 (Box 136)
  - Prejean, Helen. Dead Man Walking. New York: Random House., 1993 (Box 136)
  - Szanto, George. The Underside of Stones. New York: Harper and Row., 1990 (Box 136)
  - Parini, Jay. Benjamin's Crossing. New York: Henry Hold and Company., 1997 (Box 136)
  - Francke, Linda Bird. Ground Zero. New York: Simon and Schuster., 1997 (Box 136)
  - Goodwin, Doris Kearns. Wait Until Next Year. New York: Simon and Schuster., 1997 (Box 136)
  - Moran, William. The Belles of New England. New York: Thomas Dunne Books., 2002 (Box 136)
  - Chandra Vikram. Read Earth and Pouring Rain. New York: Little Brown and Company., 1995 (Box 136)
  - Rosen, Jonathan. Eve's Apple. New York: Random House., 1997 (Box 136)
  - Goodman, Allegra. Kaaterskill Falls. New York: The Dial Press., 1998 (Box 136)
  - Barnouw, Erik. Conglomerates and the Media. New York: The New Press., 1997 (Box 136)
  - Ferro, Robert. Second Son. New York: Crown Publisher., 1988 (Box 136)
  - Morgan, Thomas b. Snyder's Walk. New York: Doubleday and Company., 1987 (Box 136)
  - Starer, Robert. Continuo: A Life in Music. New York: Random House., 1987 (Box 136)
  - Schwartz, Howard. Elijah's Violin and Other Jewish Fairy Tales. New York: Harper and Row., 1983 (Box 136)
  - Hawkes, John. Sweet William. New York: Simon and Schuster., 1993 (Box 136)
  - Bernstein, Jeremy. The Life it Brings. New York: Tricknor and Fields., 1987 (Box 136)
  - Nader, Ralph and William Taylor. The Big Boys. New York: Pantheon Books., 1986 (Box 137)
  - Horsmanden, Daniel. The New York Conspiracy. Boston: Beacon Press., 1971 (Box 137)
  - Marcus, J.S. Captain's Fire. New York: Alfred A. Knopf., 1996 (Box 137)
  - Hale, Leslie. Hanging in the Balance. London: Jonathan Cape., 1962 (Box 137)
  - Gordon, Mary. The Shadow Man. New York: Random House., 1996 (Box 137)
  - Levi-Strauss, Claude. Tristes Tropiques. New York: Atheneum., 1981 (Box 137)
  - Allen, Charles (ed). Tales from the Dark Continent. New York: St. Martin's Press., 1979 (Box 137)
  - Ermelino, Louisa. Joey Dee Gets Wise. New York: St. Martin's Press., 1991 (Box 137)
  - Johnson, Fenton. Geography of the Heart. New York: Scribner., 1996 (Box 137)
  - Grant: Linda. The Cast Iron Shore. London: Picador., 1996 (Box 137)
  - Gifford, Don. The Farther Shore. New York: The Atlantic Monthly Press., 1990 (Box 137)
  - Doctorow, E.L. City of God. New York: Random House., 2000 (Box 137)
  - Doctorow, E.L. Creationists. New York: Random House., 2006 (Box 137)
  - Avedon, John F. In Exile from the Land of Snows. New York: Alfred A. Knopf., 1984 (Box 138)
  - Bruner, Jerome S. The Mind of a Mnemonist. Cambridge: Harvard University Press., 1968 (Box 138)
  - Sheed, Wilfrid. In Love with Daylight. New York: Simon and Schuster., 1995 (Box 138)
  - Naipaul, V.S. India. New York: Vintage Books., 1978 (Box 138)
  - Michell, John. Secrets of the Stones. Middlesex: Penguin Books., 1977 (Box 138)
  - Miller, Perry (ed). Major Writers of America. New York: Harcourt, Brace and World., 1966 (Box 138)
  - Vidal, Gore. United States: Essays 1952-1992. New York: Random House., 1993 (Box 138)
  - Fussell, Paul (ed). The Norton Book of Travel. New York: W.W. Norton and Co., 1987 (Box 138)
  - Pollak, Richard. The Creation of Dr. B. New York: Simon and Schuster., 1997 (Box 138)
  - Mitgang, Herbert. Dangerous Dossiers. New York: Donald I. Fine, Inc., 1988 (Box 138)
  - Levinson, Sanford. Constitutional Faith. Princeton: Princeton University Press., 1988 (Box 138)
  - Breasted, Charles. Pioneer to the Past. Chicago: University of Chicago Press., 1943 (Box 138)
- Oversize Series II: Manuscripts
  - Subseries A: Novels
    - The Book of Daniel- celophane wall chart with notes and plot, undated (Box 174)
    - The Book of Daniel (galleys with corrections), undated (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Loon Lake (first revised galleys), undated (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified translation (galleys), undated (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - World's Fair storyboard panels [1 of 2] (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - World's Fair storyboard panels [2 of 2] (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B: Short Fiction
    - "The Writer in the Family" (galleys for Cosmopolitan), undated (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Subseries C: Non-Fiction
    - Oversize Non-Fiction galleys with corrections, undated (Box 70, Folder 5)